<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/">
    <title>Fodi&#x27;s blog</title>
    <link href="https://blog.fodi.be/feed.xml" rel="self" />
    <link href="https://blog.fodi.be" />
    <updated>2022-12-01T10:26:09+01:00</updated>
    <author>
        <name>Fodi</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://blog.fodi.be</id>

    <entry>
        <title>Day One</title>
        <author>
            <name>Fodi</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://blog.fodi.be/day-one/"/>
        <id>https://blog.fodi.be/day-one/</id>

        <updated>2022-12-01T10:26:09+01:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                    I'm starting an experiment today. My virtual idea drawer is a mess and I need to do something about it.
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                <p>I'm starting an experiment today. My virtual idea drawer is a mess and I need to do something about it. Google Keep notes, text files all over my Dropbox, freaking audio recordings on my phone...</p>
<p>About a month ago I decided that I have to put a pause on making money (working on other people's stuff) because I clearly failed at my attempt to mix jobs with pet projects / creative hobbies in a healthy ratio. So I'm designating this December as "get your (own) shit together" month.</p>
<p>Today I'm starting this blog and I'll update it every day in December, hoping that publicly logging my progress helps me stay on track.</p>
<p>As first order of business I'm taking inventory and organizing all ideas, abandoned projects and half-assed attempts and putting them on either a "might do" or "probably won't do" pile. After that's done, I'm going to choose the first one either by preference or at random and get hacking and blogging.</p>
<p>Although I'm slightly terrified of it, but I'm also planning to stream stuff (especially game development), but I'm not quite sure that's a good idea at this point. We'll see.</p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
</feed>
