<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/">
    <title>Fodi&#x27;s blog on gamedev</title>
    <link href="https://blog.fodi.be/feed.xml" rel="self" />
    <link href="https://blog.fodi.be" />
    <updated>2023-11-18T11:12:41+01:00</updated>
    <author>
        <name>Fodi</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://blog.fodi.be</id>

    <entry>
        <title>HunJam 2023: Tower Offense 2000</title>
        <author>
            <name>Fodi</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://blog.fodi.be/hunjam-2023-tower-offense-2000/"/>
        <id>https://blog.fodi.be/hunjam-2023-tower-offense-2000/</id>
        <media:content url="https://blog.fodi.be/media/posts/37/screenshot1.png" medium="image" />
            <category term="Ended"/>
            <category term="2023"/>

        <updated>2023-11-18T11:12:41+01:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://blog.fodi.be/media/posts/37/screenshot1.png" alt="" />
                    Tibor and I attended our first ever offline game jam this weekend and we're quite happy with what we made&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <p><img src="https://blog.fodi.be/media/posts/37/screenshot1.png" class="type:primaryImage" alt="" /></p>
                <p>Tibor and I attended our first ever offline game jam this weekend and we're quite happy with what we made :)</p>
<p><a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/2037711149909497/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">HunJam 2023</a> was freaking awesome! I might update this post later with a proper post mortem, but right now I'm freaking beat, sitting on the train home, so without further ado, here's what we built this weekend:</p>
<p>Tower Offense 2000 on Itch: <a href="https://lasermagnet.itch.io/hunjam2023">https://lasermagnet.itch.io/hunjam2023</a></p>
<p>Or you can also play it here: <a href="https://play.lasermagnet.com/HunJam2023/">https://play.lasermagnet.com/HunJam2023/</a></p>
<p><strong>Update: turns out <a href="https://www.facebook.com/permalink.php?story_fbid=pfbid02t4bbHG2JPeF9BKMJjtqFmiCAyS2izfXGGoPidMCbQ7uKqusuGi1AZ1s38TwtjjZel&amp;id=61550812517788" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">the jam judges liked what we cooked up</a> :) we are stoked!</strong></p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Bouncy Block Buster</title>
        <author>
            <name>Fodi</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://blog.fodi.be/bouncy-block-buster/"/>
        <id>https://blog.fodi.be/bouncy-block-buster/</id>
        <media:content url="https://blog.fodi.be/media/posts/36/bbb-itch-cover.png" medium="image" />
            <category term="Prototype phase"/>
            <category term="Continuing"/>
            <category term="2023"/>

        <updated>2023-10-29T19:04:40+01:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://blog.fodi.be/media/posts/36/bbb-itch-cover.png" alt="" />
                    We participated in a game jam with Tibor this weekend, made a precision / physics puzzle heavily inspired by BBTAN.
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <p><img src="https://blog.fodi.be/media/posts/36/bbb-itch-cover.png" class="type:primaryImage" alt="" /></p>
                <p>We participated in a game jam with Tibor this weekend, made a precision / physics puzzle heavily inspired by BBTAN.</p>
<p>You can play it <a href="https://lasermagnet.itch.io/icojam-2023" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">on Itch</a> or <a href="https://play.lasermagnet.com/BBB/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">on LaserMagnet.com</a> (use the latter if you want to add it to your home screen). We have tons more ideas on how to proceed, hopefully we won't abandon this project anytime soon :)</p>
<p><strong>Update 1:</strong> I made a time-lapse video of the development process and <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=o56Y4H1mUqs" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">uploaded it to YouTube</a>. Check it out if that's your thing!</p>
<div class="post__iframe"><iframe loading="lazy" width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/o56Y4H1mUqs" title="YouTube video player" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen"></iframe></div>
<p>Also, I fixed a couple of bugs, the post-jam version (1.0.9) can be found <a href="https://play.lasermagnet.com/BBB/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">here</a>.</p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>SnakeyPong</title>
        <author>
            <name>Fodi</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://blog.fodi.be/snakeypong/"/>
        <id>https://blog.fodi.be/snakeypong/</id>
        <media:content url="https://blog.fodi.be/media/posts/35/snakeypong.png" medium="image" />
            <category term="Prototype phase"/>
            <category term="Continuing"/>
            <category term="2023"/>

        <updated>2023-07-31T13:28:16+02:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://blog.fodi.be/media/posts/35/snakeypong.png" alt="" />
                    About a week ago I've unearthed an old doodle (a simple "free angle" snake) and made the food bounce around.
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <p><img src="https://blog.fodi.be/media/posts/35/snakeypong.png" class="type:primaryImage" alt="" /></p>
                <p>About a week ago I've unearthed an old doodle (a simple "free angle" snake) and made the food bounce around.</p>
<p>You control a snake with the keyboard (press A / D) or the touch screen (tap the left / right side) and you have to pick up the food which bounces off the walls and the snake as well. I have a bunch of ideas to try out, but it's already fairly fun, although it's a bit of a performance hog at the moment.</p>
<p>Check out where this project goes (usually nowhere, but who knows), <a href="https://fodi.itch.io/snakeypong" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">try SnakeyPong on Itch!</a></p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>[List] Twists and combinations</title>
        <author>
            <name>Fodi</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://blog.fodi.be/list-interesting-sounding-combinations/"/>
        <id>https://blog.fodi.be/list-interesting-sounding-combinations/</id>
            <category term="Lists"/>
            <category term="Idea phase"/>

        <updated>2023-06-08T08:30:11+02:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                    No details, just one liners here. Airmech + Don't Starve: an open world exploration / crafting / survival game where&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                <p>No details, just one liners here.</p>
<ul>
<li>Airmech + Don't Starve: an open world exploration / crafting / survival game where you can switch between ground and air travel at any time</li>
<li>Mahjong with polyominos: match shapes and/or symbols</li>
<li>Unrailed + Pipe Dream with polyominos: place polyomino shaped rails quickly so the train does not derail, can't choose the shape, but can place anywhere in any rotation</li>
<li>Zuma (or something similar) with multiplayer: either PvP or co-op</li>
<li>Snake + Osmos: small snakes are eaten by big ones</li>
<li>Crimsonland, but you can teleport out of a sticky situation (press a button, quickly choose new location within time limit and radius)
<ul>
<li>additional twist: clone player instead of teleporting and control both of them (until one of them dies)</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Katamari, but 2D: either side view or top-down, possibly featuring a bunch of googly eyes</li>
</ul>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Ludum Dare 53: Something Something Delivery Something</title>
        <author>
            <name>Fodi</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://blog.fodi.be/ludum-dare-53/"/>
        <id>https://blog.fodi.be/ludum-dare-53/</id>
        <media:content url="https://blog.fodi.be/media/posts/33/ssds.jpg" medium="image" />
            <category term="Prototype phase"/>
            <category term="Ended"/>
            <category term="Changelog"/>
            <category term="2023"/>

        <updated>2023-07-31T13:28:33+02:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://blog.fodi.be/media/posts/33/ssds.jpg" alt="" />
                    I participated in the last Ludum Dare jam (#53) and made something that is not great but at least playable.
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <p><img src="https://blog.fodi.be/media/posts/33/ssds.jpg" class="type:primaryImage" alt="" /></p>
                <p>I participated in the last Ludum Dare jam (#53) and<span style="color: var(--text-primary-color); font-family: var(--editor-font-family); font-size: inherit; font-weight: var(--font-weight-normal);"> made something that is not great but at least playable. And it only took me a month to finish writing the postmortem! :)</span></p>
<p>The theme <strong>delivery</strong> was published at 3 AM CEST on Saturday, I encountered it around 7 o'clock, alerted Tibor, finished booting up and biked down to Kollabor, where I usually work. We decided to work remotely, had a quick kickoff call at around 9 about ideas. The first idea was about food delivery from restaurants to homes on a kinda-3D top-down city map using trebuchets. I spent half an hour researching how much work would it take to allow the player to just input a name of a real city (at which point the game would fetch map data via Google Maps / OpenStreetMap) and use it as a base and came to the conclusion that it's out of the question due to the 3-day deadline of the jam.</p>
<p>After some quick scaffolding in Construct 3 and another call I floated the idea of an Overcooked + Kingdom hybrid (2D side-view food preparation frenzy) with a hint of Angry Birds (delivering the finished food to the right home using a big-ass trebuchet/sling), then quickly reduced it down to just the delivery part, but using a sort of drone that the player can actively control to navigate around obstacles like in Flappy Bird. The <a href="https://send.games/u/x5kgn/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">first build</a> at 10:50 included the basic movement, obstacles and controls (Space to climb), the <a href="https://send.games/u/3kxzd/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">second build</a> at 11:25 had the basic pick up and delivery stuff (I, J, K keys for the 3 different items). Some more work and a lunch break followed.</p>
<p>I finished the <a href="https://send.games/u/s8vt7/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">third build</a> at 13:25; in this we experimented with a slightly different control scheme (W/A/D for movement + similar touch controls), allowing the player to turn around at any time. Tibor raised some good points regarding the control scheme and suggested that we add some angle to the drops for realism, so I first got rid of manual turning in the <a href="https://send.games/u/abna7"></a><a href="https://send.games/u/abna7" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">fourth build</a> at 13:53 and added a special wall type that turns the player around in the <a href="https://send.games/u/yw25i" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">fifth</a> at 14:06.</p>
<p>Some more ideation followed and I've added item and target spawners and basic respawn logic in <a href="https://send.games/u/q4pvh" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">build six</a> at 15:09. A couple of minutes later I added numpad controls in <a href="https://send.games/u/fe4ei">build seven</a>, then started to prepare the project for Tibor, so he can start designing levels and alter level rules just by editing some variables. <a href="https://send.games/u/f9sq2" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Build eight</a> included a super small test level (which can be skipped by pressing N) and was the last export for that day at 15:46, then I fixed a few bugs and we both went to a friend's house to conclude day one and consume the things we usually consume at such events.</p>
<p>On Sunday it was almost 11 AM when I managed to boot up and sit down in front of my computer, get a todo list going and contact Tibor. I decided to add some juice by adding shadow light / shadow caster and sine movement behaviors to stuff which resulted in <a href="https://send.games/u/beapf" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">build nine</a> at 11:39, then I added touchscreen UI and automatic respawn in <a href="https://send.games/u/ntuvt"></a><a href="https://send.games/u/ntuvt" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">build ten</a> at 12:21 and cycled to my parents for lunch.</p>
<p>I was back in front of the screen at around half 3 and got crackin'. A few hours and a couple of meetings later I finished <a href="https://send.games/u/tkc9h" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">build eleven</a> at 18:47, which included better touch UI, ammo pickups, shooting, and the first enemy type. After some testing, balancing and bug squashing, I've finished the day with <a href="https://send.games/u/siaxf/"></a><a href="https://send.games/u/siaxf/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">build twelve</a> at 19:40 and a quick call with Tibor about level design.</p>
<p>We picked up around 10 AM on Monday, I've included Tibor's work-in-progress levels in <a href="https://send.games/u/jnrvj"></a><a href="https://send.games/u/jnrvj" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">build thirteen</a> at 10:56. In the afternoon I started replacing the placeholder assets with better looking ones (by <a href="https://little-martian.itch.io/retro-texture-pack" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Little Martian</a> and <a href="https://zrghr.itch.io/pixel-art-loot-pixelliverse"></a><a href="https://zrghr.itch.io/pixel-art-loot-pixelliverse" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Cassius</a>) and building a tutorial to introduce the mechanics gradually for players. I sent <a href="https://send.games/u/9iccx" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">build fourteen</a> to Tibor for testing at 18:34, and fixed bugs in <a href="https://send.games/u/q4p8f/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">build fifteen</a> half an hour later. Based on his feedback I finished <a href="https://send.games/u/q9ue4" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">build sixteen</a> at 21:09, then I threw together a flimsy menu screen (yeah, I'll take the usual please!), fixed some more bugs and uploaded the <a href="https://lasermagnet.itch.io/ludum-dare-53-jam-version">final version</a> around midnight. For some reason the HTML5 build didn't work on the <a href="https://ldjam.com/events/ludum-dare/53/something-something-delivery-something">LDJAM</a> page, so the final resting place of <strong>Something Something Delivery Something</strong> (obviously named a couple of minutes before publishing) is on Itch. I haven't touched it since and based on previous experience I probably won't either.</p>
<p>And the conclusion? It was fun, exhausting, a great learning experience and I'll remember those three days fondly. And I'm looking forward to the next game jam I'll be able to participate in.</p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>TowerBall (working title)</title>
        <author>
            <name>Fodi</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://blog.fodi.be/towerball-working-title/"/>
        <id>https://blog.fodi.be/towerball-working-title/</id>
        <media:content url="https://blog.fodi.be/media/posts/32/TowerBall-EarlyPreview.png" medium="image" />
            <category term="Prototype phase"/>
            <category term="Continuing"/>
            <category term="2023"/>

        <updated>2023-05-27T12:09:29+02:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://blog.fodi.be/media/posts/32/TowerBall-EarlyPreview.png" alt="" />
                    After some playtesting, movement tweaking and expanding the test level, I decided to add TowerBall to the 2023 prototypes list.
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <p><img src="https://blog.fodi.be/media/posts/32/TowerBall-EarlyPreview.png" class="type:primaryImage" alt="" /></p>
                <p>After some playtesting, movement tweaking and expanding the test level, I decided to add TowerBall to the 2023 prototypes list.</p>
<p>The latest version is <a href="https://play.lasermagnet.com/TowerBall/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">available here</a>, it's optimized for touchscreen devices and portrait orientation, but it's playable with a mouse and a landscape viewport as well. Feel free "install" or "add it to home screen" on your phone (eg. with Google Chrome), it works offline and also lets you know if a new build is available. You just have to restart it to update to the latest version, there's no need to "reinstall it" .</p>
<p>I'm going to keep playtesting it and ask a few friends to do the same. Once movement and the controls feel right, I'm going to finish the level editor so Tibor (or anyone) can get started with level design and I can add more stuff. Well, that's the plan anyway :)</p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Unable to decide, building in progress.</title>
        <author>
            <name>Fodi</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://blog.fodi.be/unable-to-decide-building-in-progress/"/>
        <id>https://blog.fodi.be/unable-to-decide-building-in-progress/</id>
        <media:content url="https://blog.fodi.be/media/posts/31/gravitygunplatformer-towerball.png" medium="image" />
            <category term="Changelog"/>

        <updated>2023-04-01T14:30:31+02:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://blog.fodi.be/media/posts/31/gravitygunplatformer-towerball.png" alt="" />
                    I forgot to post for a month and a quarter. Here's a quick recap of what I've been up to.
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <p><img src="https://blog.fodi.be/media/posts/31/gravitygunplatformer-towerball.png" class="type:primaryImage" alt="" /></p>
                <p>I forgot to post for a month and a quarter. Here's a quick recap of what I've been up to.</p>
<p>In early March we've spent some time working on a game for <a href="https://itch.io/jam/7drl-challenge-2022" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">7DRL Challenge 2022</a> (make a roguelike in a week) and <a href="https://itch.io/jam/wonderjam-4" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Wonderjam 4</a> (theme: one weapon) with a 2D platformer where the player would roam through procedurally generated interconnected rooms with a gravity gun, picking up and chucking all sorts of household objects at zombies. It was too ambitious and we've only made a <a href="https://play.lasermagnet.com/GravityGunPlatformer/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">super early prototype</a>, but I've also prepared a nice Construct 3 template with up-to-date Rot.js integration might come handy and save a bunch of time later.</p>
<p>I've also cooked up a C3 template that provides a simple in-game UI to change the rules of the game (eg. how high the player jumps, how much damage a weapon deals) and saves rule sets in slots (that are stored as JSON strings in localStorage) which can be loaded at any point. This should help with balancing games, as changes can be made by anyone in the team without the need to recompile (or even restart) the game.</p>
<p>About a week ago I started building a physics platformer (one sorta like the <a href="https://blog.fodi.be/dungeon-bouncer/">Dungeon Bouncer</a> idea but less silly) with touch / mouse control. It's temporarily called <strong>TowerBall</strong>. I'm still just exploring main mechanics (trying to do quick iterations), at the moment the player controls a ball or a cube (well, a circle or a square) that is light and bouncy at first but once it hits the ground it becomes heavy and less bouncy. The objective is to descend a "tower" and pick stuff up while avoiding hazards. A super early prototype can be found <a href="https://play.lasermagnet.com/TowerBall/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">here</a> if anyone is interested. It auto-updates to the latest public build, so if you try it in the future (and in the rare case I don't abandon the project after a week) it might play very differently. You've been warned! :)</p>
<p>As I prefer coding over level design, I'm also working on a simple tile-based level editor template (primarily for the aforementioned <strong>TowerBall</strong> project) which might end up as a separate release later.</p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Mediocre Container Package: my first attempt at Trijam</title>
        <author>
            <name>Fodi</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://blog.fodi.be/i-did-trijam-for-the-first-time/"/>
        <id>https://blog.fodi.be/i-did-trijam-for-the-first-time/</id>
        <media:content url="https://blog.fodi.be/media/posts/30/mediocre-container-package.png" medium="image" />
            <category term="Prototype phase"/>
            <category term="Ended"/>
            <category term="2023"/>

        <updated>2023-03-24T06:45:11+01:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://blog.fodi.be/media/posts/30/mediocre-container-package.png" alt="" />
                    Last weekend I took part in Trijam #206, the 3-hour single-theme game jam that takes place every weekend on Itch.
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <p><img src="https://blog.fodi.be/media/posts/30/mediocre-container-package.png" class="type:primaryImage" alt="" /></p>
                <p>Last weekend I took part in <a href="https://itch.io/jam/trijam-206" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Trijam #206</a>, the 3-hour single-theme game jam that takes place every weekend on Itch. It was super fun and quite challenging by itself, but I decided to kill multiple birds with one stone: I recorded the whole process (the screen and my actual fat face) and even narrated it (albeit in Hungarian). I'm still editing the footage, but hopefully it will be up in a few days.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, if you'd like to take a look at what I managed to put together in 3 hours, check out <a href="https://fodi.itch.io/mediocre-container-package">Mediocre Container Package</a>, the prototype of a wonky <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/212800/Super_Crate_Box/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Super Crate Box</a> clone. After the jam's voting period ended, I've pushed a minor update that fixes two issues and adds basic controller support too. The project file is also available on the Itch page if anyone is interested.</p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>PowerCharger 4269 (for Juice Jam II)</title>
        <author>
            <name>Fodi</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://blog.fodi.be/powercharger-4269-for-juice-jam-ii/"/>
        <id>https://blog.fodi.be/powercharger-4269-for-juice-jam-ii/</id>
        <media:content url="https://blog.fodi.be/media/posts/29/powercharger4269.png" medium="image" />
            <category term="Prototype phase"/>
            <category term="Ended"/>
            <category term="2023"/>

        <updated>2023-04-01T14:38:31+02:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://blog.fodi.be/media/posts/29/powercharger4269.png" alt="" />
                    Our little "studio", Lasermagnet Games (i.e. Tibor and myself) participated in GDB Juice Jam II and produced a game prototype&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <p><img src="https://blog.fodi.be/media/posts/29/powercharger4269.png" class="type:primaryImage" alt="" /></p>
                <p>Our little "studio", Lasermagnet Games (i.e. <a href="https://itch.io/profile/teebor9" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Tibor</a> and myself) participated in GDB Juice Jam II and produced a game prototype that we are quite content with as is, even though it's far from finished.</p>
<p>The main criteria was to make a game that is <strong>juicy</strong>, and after watching a <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=AJdEqssNZ-U" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">couple</a> <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=216_5nu4aVQ" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">of</a> <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=pmSAG51BybY" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">videos</a> on the topic it was clear that juiciness or getting the right "game feel" is quite an important bit that we haven't really focused on before.</p>
<p>Here are my main takeaways post-jam:</p>
<ul>
<li>From now on I'm going to use a bunch of juicy techniques from the Vlambeer cookbook in all our future games. For arcade games they should basically be mandatory.</li>
<li>We are still quite bad at time management. The day before the deadline we've made major changes to the mechanics and added a bunch of (although planned) features. The last day was about bugfixes and a very limited playtesting which meant that the game was quite unbalanced (but thankfully it's on the easier side).</li>
<li>We need to do more jams this year. It's great fun, rewarding and a great learning experience still.</li>
</ul>
<p>Without further ado: <a href="https://lasermagnet.itch.io/juice-jam-2023" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">check out PowerCharger 4269 on Itch</a>! We have plans for updates that might or might not happen.</p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Juice Jam 2023: We&#x27;re getting there.</title>
        <author>
            <name>Fodi</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://blog.fodi.be/juice-jam-2023-were-getting-there/"/>
        <id>https://blog.fodi.be/juice-jam-2023-were-getting-there/</id>
        <media:content url="https://blog.fodi.be/media/posts/28/juice-jam-2023-update.svg" medium="image" />
            <category term="Changelog"/>

        <updated>2023-02-17T13:06:17+01:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://blog.fodi.be/media/posts/28/juice-jam-2023-update.svg" alt="" />
                    We still have a fuckton to do, but our jam entry is starting to feel fun. https://lasermagnet.itch.io/juice-jam-2023
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <p><img src="https://blog.fodi.be/media/posts/28/juice-jam-2023-update.svg" class="type:primaryImage" alt="" /></p>
                <p>We still have a fuckton to do, but our jam entry is starting to feel fun.</p>
<p><a href="https://lasermagnet.itch.io/juice-jam-2023" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">https://lasermagnet.itch.io/juice-jam-2023</a></p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
</feed>
