<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/">
    <title>Fodi does gamedev</title>
    <link href="https://gamedev.fodi.be/feed.xml" rel="self" />
    <link href="https://gamedev.fodi.be" />
    <updated>2024-04-05T09:10:43+02:00</updated>
    <author>
        <name>Fodi</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://gamedev.fodi.be</id>

    <entry>
        <title>Tips for Construct 3 developers</title>
        <author>
            <name>Fodi</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://gamedev.fodi.be/tips-for-c3-developers/"/>
        <id>https://gamedev.fodi.be/tips-for-c3-developers/</id>
        <media:content url="https://gamedev.fodi.be/media/posts/50/construct-3-organization-tips.png" medium="image" />

        <updated>2024-04-04T16:56:59+02:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://gamedev.fodi.be/media/posts/50/construct-3-organization-tips.png" alt="Construct 3 project organization tips" />
                    I came up with / yoinked some practices I usually follow when working on Construct 3 projects. Warning: opinionated content.
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <p><img src="https://gamedev.fodi.be/media/posts/50/construct-3-organization-tips.png" class="type:primaryImage" alt="Construct 3 project organization tips" /></p>
                <p>I came up with / yoinked some practices I usually follow when working on Construct 3 projects. Warning: opinionated content. I'm not saying these are "best practices" in general, but maybe other C3 gamedevs might some of them useful too, so here goes.</p>
<h3>Sheet organization</h3>
<p>I usually have 4 folders in every project: <strong>Actions</strong>, <strong>Events</strong>, <strong>Functions</strong> and <strong>Values</strong>.</p>
<p>The <strong>Actions </strong>folder contains sheets that have custom actions for a single object type or family. Sheets are named after the relevant object type or family, prefixed with the letter "a", eg. <strong>aPlayers</strong>, <strong>aEnemies</strong>, <strong>aPortals</strong>.</p>
<p>The <strong>Events </strong>folder contains sheets that only have certain kind of actual events (conditions + actions), with names prefixed with the letter "e". Some examples: <strong>eCreated</strong> (containing only "on X created" events), <strong>eCollisions</strong> (with only "on collision with" and "is overlapping" events), <strong>eInput</strong> (only Keyboard / Gamepad / Mouse / Touch events), <strong>eMovement</strong> (only events with conditions of movement behaviours), et cetera.</p>
<p>The <strong>Functions </strong>folder contains sheets that only have functions in them, their names are prefixed with the letter "f". Some examples: <strong>fUI</strong> (functions that update the user interface), <strong>fLevel</strong> (level initialization, ending, etc), <strong>fUtilities</strong> (full screen toggler function, various value returning math functions, etc), et cetera.</p>
<p>The <strong>Values</strong> folder contains exactly 3 sheets that only have global variables or constants in them: <strong>vState</strong> for global game state related variables, <strong>vConstants</strong> for global constants (I prefix those with "C_") and <strong>vMacros</strong> (more on that later).</p>
<p>A single event sheet at the root level named <strong>Main</strong> (sometimes <strong>Level</strong>) that includes all sheets in the <strong>Events folder</strong> (there's no need to include sheets from the other folders, custom actions, functions and global variables/constants are always available) and nothing else. This sheet is set as the "Event sheet" on all level layouts. For menu screens I usually use a separate layout with its own event sheet.</p>
<p>I suffix all sheets with emojis (pro tip for Windows devs: press Win + comma to open the emoji panel), so I can spot them quicker when I have a metric crapton of tabs open.</p>
<p class="msg msg--highlight "><strong>Tangential sidenote</strong><br>Using emojis in names of C3 primitives, and project folders instead of single file (.c3p) projects means that you'll have file names on your filesystem that have emojis in them. This is an issue if you store them in Dropbox, as it will refuse to sync those files. Because of that, I went back to saving my projects in .c3p files and storing those in Dropbox. Dropbox saved my bacon a few times when I've accidentally saved or overwritten a project, as it keeps previous versions of files (as long as it's able to sync them to their server) which you can restore.</p>
<h3>Using "macros"</h3>
<p>I never use literal strings in conditions/actions when referencing animation names, layer names, effects, tags and such: instead, I use "macros", which are just constants I define in my vMacros sheet. Example: if I have a sprite that has an "Idle" and "Walking" animation, I create constants named "ANIM_Idle" and "ANIM_Walking" in the "vMacros" sheet with the values "Idle" and "Walking" respectively, and use those in conditions and actions instead of the string literals "Idle" and "Walking".</p>
<p>This has a couple of benefits:</p>
<ul>
<li>You get autocompletion: you just start typing the name of the constant wherever you want to use it's value in a condition or action and you don't have to worry about typos either.</li>
<li>You can use "Find all references" on the macro to find its occourences</li>
<li>I you decide you want to <a href="https://martinfowler.com/bliki/TwoHardThings.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">rename</a> "Walking" to "Running", you only have to make the change in two places: in the animation editor and the global constant. I almost never need use the search &amp; replace function because of this.</li>
</ul>
<h3>Picky blindspots (sorry)</h3>
<p>A significant amount of bugs I create are related to screwing up picking conditions: either picking something I don't want to pick, picking the wrong instance or failing to pick something. Here are some suggestions and known footguns related to object instance picking.</p>
<ul>
<li>If you only want to pick a single object, make sure that the conditions only pick one. If unsure, add a "pick nth instance" condition with the parameter "0".</li>
<li>If you're storing UIDs in (instance) variables, make their default value is a negative number (eg. -1) and not 0, since 0 could be a valid UID since it's zero indexed. When you clear the variable, also reset it to a negative number.</li>
<li>Don't forget that the timer behaviour's "On timer" condition might pick multiple instances if those instances reach their time in the same tick and you might need to put in an extra "For each" to run actions on all of them. <a href="https://www.construct.net/en/make-games/manuals/construct-3/behavior-reference/timer" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">This is mentioned in a big yellow warning box in the docs by the way.</a></li>
<li>Functions and custom actions have a similarly named option: "copy picked" and "copy all picked". If you have a custom action for an object type or family "X" and call it from an event that already picked some instances of "X", those will be passed on to the custom action even if you don't check "copy all picked" (which is for passing other non-"X" instances to the custom action).</li>
</ul>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Useful links</title>
        <author>
            <name>Fodi</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://gamedev.fodi.be/links/"/>
        <id>https://gamedev.fodi.be/links/</id>

        <updated>2024-03-22T12:40:40+01:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                    This is essentially a copy of the contents of my "GameDev" bookmarks folder. Until I figure out a better way&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                <p>This is essentially a copy of the contents of my "GameDev" bookmarks folder. Until I figure out a better way to organize them, here's a slightly chaotic list.</p>
<h2>Stuff I read / listen to when I'm not doing </h2>
<h3><a href="https://www.bscotch.net/podcast" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Coffee with Butterscotch</a></h3>
<p>A long running <strong>gamedev comedy podcast</strong> by Butterscotch Shenanigans. The perfect mix of entertaining and useful, these folks are essentially my role models.</p>
<h3><a href="https://gameaccessibilityguidelines.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Game accessibility guidelines</a></h3>
<p>A fairly comprehensive guide to inclusive game design.</p>
<h3><a href="https://ltpf.ramiismail.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Levelling The Playing Field</a></h3>
<p>Rami Ismail's <strong>blog / newsletter</strong> mostly on the <strong>marketing</strong> side of gamedev.</p>
<h2>Cheat sheets and resources for programmers</h2>
<h3><a href="https://www.redblobgames.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Red Blob Games</a></h3>
<p>A great collection of <strong>interactive visual explanations of math and algorithms</strong> on procedural generation, pathfinding and a lots of other topics related to game development.</p>
<h3><a href="https://easings.net/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Easing functions cheat sheet</a></h3>
<p>A handy visual <strong>guide to easing functions</strong>.</p>
<h2>Assets</h2>
<h3><a href="https://99sounds.org/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">99Sounds</a></h3>
<p>Curated packs of free <strong>sound effects</strong>.</p>
<h3><a href="https://itch.io/game-assets" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Itch.io game assets</a></h3>
<p>Enormous amounts of <strong>audio and visual assets</strong>, some free, some paid.</p>
<h3><a href="https://kenney.nl/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Kenney</a></h3>
<p>Also known as "Asset Jesus", Kenney Vleugels is a Dutch artist who created a huge amount of high quality <strong>2D, 3D and audio assets</strong> and made them available through this site, all under CC0 license.</p>
<h3><a href="https://lospec.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Lospec</a></h3>
<p>I'm not a visual artist, so I only use this site to find pleasant <strong>colour palettes</strong> for temporary "programmer art", but it's still awesome. They also have <strong>pixel art tutorials</strong>.</p>
<h3><a href="https://opengameart.org/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">OpenGameArt.org</a></h3>
<p>Copious amounts of free <strong>audio and visual assets</strong> with various kinds of permissive licenses.</p>
<h3><a href="https://quaternius.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Quaternius</a></h3>
<p>Not unlike Kenney, Quaternius is a super talented and generous artist specializing in high quality <strong>low-poly 3D assets</strong> made available under a CC0 license.</p>
<h2>Tools</h2>
<h3><a href="https://www.eatmy.art/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Arteater</a></h3>
<p>An awesome <strong>animation tool</strong> for turning hand drawn or painted animations into digital ones. Great for getting kids involved with digital art / gamedev.</p>
<h3><a href="https://sfbgames.itch.io/chiptone"></a><a href="https://sfbgames.itch.io/chiptone" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Chiptone</a></h3>
<p>An awesome browser based <strong>sound effect generator</strong>. It's very easy to use thanks to the included presets, but it's also very versatile if you want to get your hands dirty.</p>
<h3><a href="https://www.pmbaty.com/iosbuildenv/">iOS Build Environment for Windows</a></h3>
<p>A very useful <strong>build tool</strong> for Unity and Cordova projects targeting iOS / iPadOS.</p>
<h3><a href="https://labbed.net/software/labchirp/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">LabChirp</a></h3>
<p>A downloadable cross-platform <strong>sound effect generator</strong>.</p>
<h3><a href="https://www.omnicalculator.com/math" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Omnicalculator</a></h3>
<p>A bunch of useful <strong>articles with interactive calculators</strong> if you keep forgetting math and physics equations like me.</p>
<h2>Useful tools mostly for Construct 3 developers</h2>
<h3><a href="https://sandbox.babylonjs.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Babylon.js sandbox</a></h3>
<p>An incredibly useful tool for viewing and preparing GLTF/GLB models for use with <a href="https://kindeyegames.itch.io/c3-3dobject-alpha" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Mikal's 3D Object plugin</a>.</p>
<h3><a href="https://mp2.dk/chowdren/#construct" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Chowdren</a></h3>
<p>A 3rd party paid <strong>porting service</strong> utilizing a runtime made in C++ which implements a bunch of Construct 2/3 (and Multimedia Fusion) features. Might be a feasible alternative to the browser based runtime in some cases.</p>
<h3><a href="https://stmn.itch.io/font2bitmap" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Font to sprite font converter</a></h3>
<p>A great <strong>tool for generating sprite font sheets</strong> and padding data which you can import to your Construct project.</p>
<h3><a href="https://ondras.github.io/rot.js" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">ROT.js</a></h3>
<p>A <strong>JavaScript library</strong> for making traditional <strong>roguelike</strong> development easier. It has features like map generation, pathfinding, et cetera. Can be hooked up with Construct 3 fairly easily.</p>
<h3><a href="https://github.com/kchapelier/wavefunctioncollapse" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">WaveFunctionCollapse (JavaScript port)</a></h3>
<p>A seriously awesome <strong>JavaScript library for procedural generation</strong> based on visual patterns. I used this in our 2021 jam game prototype <a href="https://lasermagnet.itch.io/groundflipper" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Groundflipper</a>.</p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Music Miner Marty (HEJ 2024 Feb jam)</title>
        <author>
            <name>Fodi</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://gamedev.fodi.be/music-miner-marty-hej-2024-feb-jam/"/>
        <id>https://gamedev.fodi.be/music-miner-marty-hej-2024-feb-jam/</id>
        <media:content url="https://gamedev.fodi.be/media/posts/48/mmm.jpg" medium="image" />
            <category term="Prototype phase"/>
            <category term="2024"/>

        <updated>2024-03-14T12:08:58+01:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://gamedev.fodi.be/media/posts/48/mmm.jpg" alt="" />
                    We finally ventured into rhythm game territory, which has been on the Lasermagnet Games todo list for quite some time.
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <p><img src="https://gamedev.fodi.be/media/posts/48/mmm.jpg" class="type:primaryImage" alt="" /></p>
                <p>We finally ventured into rhythm game territory, which has been on the Lasermagnet Games todo list for quite some time. </p>
<p>After skipping the <a href="https://itch.io/jam/hej-2024-jan" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">January</a> edition of the Hungarian "<a href="https://haviegyjatek.itch.io/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Havi Egy Játék</a>" ("One Game a Month") jam I was delighted to find out that themes for <a href="https://itch.io/jam/hej-2024-februar" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">February</a> included "on the beat", which served as an excellent excuse to finally make a rhythm game. Tibor came up with the idea to make something like SteamWorld Dig / Spelunky but with a musical twist: swinging the pickaxe in sync with the beat.</p>
<p>We started making the game on the 29th of February (thank frack it was a leap year :) and had a relatively cozy deadline of March 5th to finish. About 70% of the process was also streamed <a href="https://www.twitch.tv/fodi_gamedev" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">on my Twitch</a>, but I'm not sure I'll upload the archives this time.</p>
<p><a href="https://lasermagnet.itch.io/music-miner-marty" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Music Miner Marty is available on Itch</a>, it already received a post-jam update (bugfixes and UX improvements only so far), the original <a href="https://lasermagnet.github.io/games/music-miner-marty-jam-version/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">jam version can be found here</a> for reference.</p>
<p>And here's a little gameplay:</p>
<p><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=gr_IzilGUKQ"><div class="post__iframe"><iframe loading="lazy" width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/gr_IzilGUKQ" title="YouTube video player" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen"></iframe></div></a></p>
<p>Naturally we have a bunch of ideas we might try to add later (combos, tougher blocks, touch input support, enemies, falling blocks, et cetera), but no promises of course :)</p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>My videos on gamedev</title>
        <author>
            <name>Fodi</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://gamedev.fodi.be/my-videos-on-gamedev/"/>
        <id>https://gamedev.fodi.be/my-videos-on-gamedev/</id>

        <updated>2024-03-12T12:06:49+01:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                    For convenience, here's a list of all my gamedev-related videos in reverse chronological order. Archived streams, demos and gameplays, development&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                <p>For convenience, here's a list of all my gamedev-related videos in reverse chronological order. Archived streams, demos and gameplays, development time-lapses, et cetera.</p>
<h2>2024</h2>
<p><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=gr_IzilGUKQ" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Music Miner Marty (jam version) gameplay</a></p>
<p><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=YMfvmv10Vag" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Rule of Threes development stream (in Hungarian)</a></p>
<h2>2023</h2>
<p><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ak8LVGw3EEc" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Magic Pandemic development stream (in Hungarian)</a></p>
<p><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=o56Y4H1mUqs" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Bouncy Block Buster development time-lapse</a></p>
<h2>2022</h2>
<p><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=FpMWSso46R0" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">AruControl for Construct 3 (free template) demo</a></p>
<p> </p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Rule of Threes (Trijam #256)</title>
        <author>
            <name>Fodi</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://gamedev.fodi.be/rule-of-threes-trijam-256-2/"/>
        <id>https://gamedev.fodi.be/rule-of-threes-trijam-256-2/</id>
        <media:content url="https://gamedev.fodi.be/media/posts/46/ruleofthrees.png" medium="image" />
            <category term="Stream"/>
            <category term="Prototype phase"/>
            <category term="Projects"/>
            <category term="2024"/>

        <updated>2024-02-12T19:07:12+01:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://gamedev.fodi.be/media/posts/46/ruleofthrees.png" alt="Rule of Threes" />
                    Yesterday I did another live stream and made a puzzle game in three hours for Trijam. It's playable, but wonky.
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <p><img src="https://gamedev.fodi.be/media/posts/46/ruleofthrees.png" class="type:primaryImage" alt="Rule of Threes" /></p>
                <p>Yesterday I did another live stream and made a puzzle game in three hours for Trijam. It's playable, but wonky.</p>
<p>The jam's theme was "only three" and this time the game's concept came pretty quickly during a post-lunch coffee just a couple hours before I started making it. I wanted to create something that looks a bit like Bejeweled et al (colorful shapes in a grid), but plays more like a sudoku or nonogram puzzle. I like those kinds of "deterministic puzzles", but as I've anticipated, coming up with a proper level generation algorithm is not an easy task (for me at least). So until I have a eureka moment and figure out how to generate levels that can be solved without any ambiguity, the game stays in it's current janky state.</p>
<p>If you're willing to give it a go despite this, you can find <a href="https://fodi.itch.io/trijam-256" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Rule of Threes on tch</a>. I also uploaded the stream archive to <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=YMfvmv10Vag" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">YouTube</a> - and yes, it's in Hungarian again. I'm considering doing the next one in English though.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=YMfvmv10Vag"><div class="post__iframe"><iframe loading="lazy" width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/YMfvmv10Vag" title="YouTube video player" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen"></iframe></div></a></p>
<p> </p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>First stream of the year</title>
        <author>
            <name>Fodi</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://gamedev.fodi.be/first-stream-of-the-year/"/>
        <id>https://gamedev.fodi.be/first-stream-of-the-year/</id>
        <media:content url="https://gamedev.fodi.be/media/posts/44/trijam255.png" medium="image" />
            <category term="Stream"/>
            <category term="Journal"/>

        <updated>2024-02-03T23:37:17+01:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://gamedev.fodi.be/media/posts/44/trijam255.png" alt="Our unfinished and untitled prototype for Trijam #255" />
                    The VOD is up, edited YouTube video is coming soon. Clocked in at 4 hours, a prototype is coming along.
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <p><img src="https://gamedev.fodi.be/media/posts/44/trijam255.png" class="type:primaryImage" alt="Our unfinished and untitled prototype for Trijam #255" /></p>
                <p>The VOD is up, edited YouTube video is coming soon. Clocked in at 4 hours, a prototype is coming along.</p>
<p>Twitch:<br><a href="https://www.twitch.tv/videos/2052004625">https://www.twitch.tv/videos/2052004625</a></p>
<p>Itch:<br><a href="https://lasermagnet.itch.io/trijam-255">https://lasermagnet.itch.io/trijam-255</a></p>
<p>Ch:<br>🇨🇭</p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>2023 recap and a new challenge</title>
        <author>
            <name>Fodi</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://gamedev.fodi.be/2023-recap-and-a-new-challenge/"/>
        <id>https://gamedev.fodi.be/2023-recap-and-a-new-challenge/</id>
        <media:content url="https://gamedev.fodi.be/media/posts/42/2023-recap.svg" medium="image" />
            <category term="Journal"/>

        <updated>2024-01-07T11:24:38+01:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://gamedev.fodi.be/media/posts/42/2023-recap.svg" alt="" />
                    What happened in 2023 and why did I not make 20 game prototypes like I wanted to? A short postmortem.
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <p><img src="https://gamedev.fodi.be/media/posts/42/2023-recap.svg" class="type:primaryImage" alt="" /></p>
                <div class="post__inner post__entry">
<p>What happened in 2023 and why did I not make 20 game prototypes like I wanted to? A short postmortem.</p>
<p>Around the end of January last year <a href="file:///D:/Dropbox/Projects/Publii/fodis-blog-on-gamedev/preview/a-brief-intermission-and-a-challenge/index.html">I challenged myself</a> to build 20 video game prototypes in 2023. I only managed to build 8 on my own (some of them with <a href="https://itch.io/profile/teebor9" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Tibor</a>), so one could say I failed to reach my target.</p>
<p>In March I landed my first paid gamedev gig thanks to the guys over at <a href="https://bardtest.gg/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">BardTest.gg.</a> They provide tools for members of the esports community with which they can measure and strengthen their skills like hand-eye coordination, multitasking, decision-making under pressure, et cetera. Their users have access to a variety of mini-games (that's where I come in), which feature core mechanics of first-person shooters and MOBAs. After each play session the players are scored and ranked based on how well they did compared to other users and professional players. Last year I finished the development of 14 mini-games for them, out of which 12 are publicly accessible on their platform at the moment. Counting these, I did manage to reach 20 prototypes, although that wasn't exactly my intention when I came up with the challenge back in February.</p>
<p>My intention was to turn a portion of my ever-increasing idea pile into playable prototypes. One of them was to make a turn-based game that runs on a big screen in a public location that any passerby can control using their phones. I cobbled together the proof of concept for the communication "framework", which worked fine. I became so sure I was going to turn it into an actual game that I bought a used TV and rented an office with a big shop window on a semi-busy street. It worked out great as a new workplace (although I was alone most of the time, so my initial productivity boost dwindled in a few months), but the TV was only collecting dust for 6 months, then my contract was up. We even built a <a href="file:///D:/Dropbox/Projects/Publii/fodis-blog-on-gamedev/preview/bouncy-block-buster/index.html">turn-based physics puzzle</a> for a game jam in July with Tibor, which I could've adapted to this framework... but I didn't. Not sure why.</p>
<p>In October I moved offices and started working from a small flat with a friend of mine (Viktor) who's also a software developer now. This setup provided a productivity boost that still lasts today, most days we're both in the office working on our separate projects. </p>
<p>At the end of November I tried streaming on <a href="https://www.twitch.tv/fodi_gamedev" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Twitch</a> the first time, <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ak8LVGw3EEc" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">made a short video game from scratch in three hours</a> for TriJam, which was fun, and it only took me 7 months to muster the courage (just checked, I bought the mic in April). I no longer feel completely terrified of it, so I'm planning on streaming from time to time.</p>
<p>My new challenge for 2024 is to make at least 12 video game prototypes (not counting paid gigs this time) and at least 12 game development streams / videos, ideally one every month.</p>
</div>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Magic Pandemic (Trijam #247)</title>
        <author>
            <name>Fodi</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://gamedev.fodi.be/magic-pandemic-for-trijam-247/"/>
        <id>https://gamedev.fodi.be/magic-pandemic-for-trijam-247/</id>
        <media:content url="https://gamedev.fodi.be/media/posts/38/magicpandemic-screenshot.png" medium="image" />
            <category term="Prototype phase"/>
            <category term="Projects"/>
            <category term="2023"/>

        <updated>2023-11-27T11:36:11+01:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://gamedev.fodi.be/media/posts/38/magicpandemic-screenshot.png" alt="" />
                    Last Sunday I had my first Twitch stream (in Hungarian), improvising a game for the 3 hour game jam, Trijam.
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <p><img src="https://gamedev.fodi.be/media/posts/38/magicpandemic-screenshot.png" class="type:primaryImage" alt="" /></p>
                <p>Last Sunday I had my first Twitch stream (in Hungarian), improvising a game for the 3 hour game jam, <a href="https://itch.io/jam/trijam-247" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Trijam</a>.</p>
<p>I was slightly nervous, but in the end I had a lot of fun and will probably do this sort of thing again. It's not my intention to grow a huge follower base and I currently have zero interest in taking streaming seriously, but I figured it could work as a coping strategy to mitigate some of my ADHD-like symptoms, like postponing fun hobby stuff indefinitely all the time. In the last few months I was checking out <a href="https://itch.io/jams" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">game jams on Itch</a> almost every weekend, writing little notes and ideas for the ones I found interesting, but I either didn't manage to get started on any of them, or if I did, I lost momentum after a few hours. I'm hoping live streaming could help with that, even if basically no one is watching it.</p>
<p>I'm not sure it's worth anyone's time, but since it wasn't much additional effort, I put the edited stream up on YouTube. On the off chance you speak Hungarian and would like to check it out, it's <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ak8LVGw3EEc" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">right here</a>.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ak8LVGw3EEc"><div class="post__iframe"><iframe loading="lazy" width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/ak8LVGw3EEc" title="YouTube video player" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen"></iframe></div></a></p>
<p>The game turned out to be a pretty simple one (no surprise there), partly because I was narrating everything I was doing and because I wanted to stay inside the 3 hour window. You can <a href="https://fodi.itch.io/trijam-247" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">play Magic Pandemic on Itch</a> if you want, the back story is on the page, instructions and controls are shown in-game. It supports 4 control schemes: gamepad, keyboard, touch and technically mouse as well, but I do not recommend that. It seems to be running okay on mobile devices too, but the text UI glitches a little on my Android phone.</p>
<p>If you feel the need to follow me on <a href="https://www.youtube.com/@Fodi_be" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">YouTube</a>, <a href="https://www.twitch.tv/fodi_gamedev" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Twitch</a>, <a href="https://fodi.itch.io/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Itch</a>, <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=1iHG7YRorgM" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Tich, Mick, Beaky, Dozy or Dave Dee</a>, please feel to do so! :)</p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>HunJam 2023: Tower Offense 2000</title>
        <author>
            <name>Fodi</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://gamedev.fodi.be/hunjam-2023-tower-offense-2000/"/>
        <id>https://gamedev.fodi.be/hunjam-2023-tower-offense-2000/</id>
        <media:content url="https://gamedev.fodi.be/media/posts/37/screenshot1.png" medium="image" />
            <category term="Prototype phase"/>
            <category term="Projects"/>
            <category term="2023"/>

        <updated>2023-10-29T19:01:06+01:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://gamedev.fodi.be/media/posts/37/screenshot1.png" alt="" />
                    Tibor and I attended our first ever offline game jam this weekend and we're quite happy with what we made&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <p><img src="https://gamedev.fodi.be/media/posts/37/screenshot1.png" class="type:primaryImage" alt="" /></p>
                <p>Tibor and I attended our first ever offline game jam this weekend and we're quite happy with what we made :)</p>
<p><a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/2037711149909497/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">HunJam 2023</a> was freaking awesome! I might update this post later with a proper post mortem, but right now I'm freaking beat, sitting on the train home, so without further ado, here's what we built this weekend:</p>
<p>Tower Offense 2000 on Itch: <a href="https://lasermagnet.itch.io/hunjam2023">https://lasermagnet.itch.io/hunjam2023</a></p>
<p>Or you can also play it here: <a href="https://play.lasermagnet.com/HunJam2023/">https://play.lasermagnet.com/HunJam2023/</a></p>
<p><strong>Update: turns out <a href="https://www.facebook.com/permalink.php?story_fbid=pfbid02t4bbHG2JPeF9BKMJjtqFmiCAyS2izfXGGoPidMCbQ7uKqusuGi1AZ1s38TwtjjZel&amp;id=61550812517788" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">the jam judges liked what we cooked up</a> :) we are stoked!</strong></p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Bouncy Block Buster</title>
        <author>
            <name>Fodi</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://gamedev.fodi.be/bouncy-block-buster/"/>
        <id>https://gamedev.fodi.be/bouncy-block-buster/</id>
        <media:content url="https://gamedev.fodi.be/media/posts/36/bbb-itch-cover.png" medium="image" />
            <category term="Prototype phase"/>
            <category term="Projects"/>
            <category term="2023"/>

        <updated>2023-07-31T13:27:46+02:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://gamedev.fodi.be/media/posts/36/bbb-itch-cover.png" alt="" />
                    We participated in a game jam with Tibor this weekend, made a precision / physics puzzle heavily inspired by BBTAN.
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <p><img src="https://gamedev.fodi.be/media/posts/36/bbb-itch-cover.png" class="type:primaryImage" alt="" /></p>
                <p>We participated in a game jam with Tibor this weekend, made a precision / physics puzzle heavily inspired by BBTAN.</p>
<p>You can play it <a href="https://lasermagnet.itch.io/icojam-2023" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">on Itch</a> or <a href="https://play.lasermagnet.com/BBB/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">on LaserMagnet.com</a> (use the latter if you want to add it to your home screen). We have tons more ideas on how to proceed, hopefully we won't abandon this project anytime soon :)</p>
<p><strong>Update 1:</strong> I made a time-lapse video of the development process and <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=o56Y4H1mUqs" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">uploaded it to YouTube</a>. Check it out if that's your thing!</p>
<div class="post__iframe"><iframe loading="lazy" width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/o56Y4H1mUqs" title="YouTube video player" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen"></iframe></div>
<p>Also, I fixed a couple of bugs, the post-jam version (1.0.9) can be found <a href="https://play.lasermagnet.com/BBB/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">here</a>.</p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
</feed>
