<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/">
    <title>Fodi&#x27;s blog</title>
    <link href="https://blog.fodi.be/feed.xml" rel="self" />
    <link href="https://blog.fodi.be" />
    <updated>2022-12-06T10:56:56+01:00</updated>
    <author>
        <name>Fodi</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://blog.fodi.be</id>

    <entry>
        <title>Day Three</title>
        <author>
            <name>Fodi</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://blog.fodi.be/day-three/"/>
        <id>https://blog.fodi.be/day-three/</id>
            <category term="Blog"/>

        <updated>2022-12-05T22:08:21+01:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                    Today was unproductive. I've added a post about using weird tech in games though, but it's just a stub at&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                <p>Today was unproductive. I've added a post about <a href="https://blog.fodi.be/uncommon-tech-for-video-games/">using weird tech in games</a> though, but it's just a stub at this point and will be extended later.</p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Uncommon tech for video games</title>
        <author>
            <name>Fodi</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://blog.fodi.be/uncommon-tech-for-video-games/"/>
        <id>https://blog.fodi.be/uncommon-tech-for-video-games/</id>
            <category term="Idea phase"/>
            <category term="GameDev"/>

        <updated>2022-12-06T10:56:56+01:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                    A few of my video game ideas are based on or based around some tech that is not very common&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                <p>A few of my video game ideas are based on or based around some tech that is not very common in video games. I considered using the term "gimmickware" to describe this category, but that sounds a bit negative. But yeah, these might sound gimmicky.</p>
<h2>Fiducial markers (ArUco and friends)</h2>
<p>Shortly after I started working for <a href="https://kollabor.hu/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Kollabor</a> I came across a very nice educational board game / video game mix called <a href="https://scottiego.com/en/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Scottie Go!</a> by a Polish company. It introduces basic programming concepts like commands, variables, functions and loops in a similar vein to <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Logo_(programming_language)" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Logo</a>: the player can tell a nice cartoon character where to go on screen (and there are increasingly difficult levels to beat). They also added a twist: there are physical pieces of "blocks" printed with the commands and the player has to lay them out on a table, then take a picture of it with a device camera to "execute the code". Those blocks used inverted ArUco markers as I've found out and I quickly stumbled upon an <a href="https://docs.opencv.org/4.x/d5/dae/tutorial_aruco_detection.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">OpenCV based implementation</a> (I hacked together an Android app to stream detected markers over the WebSocket protocol) and <a href="https://github.com/jcmellado/js-aruco" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">one that is pure Javascript</a>. I've used <a href="https://github.com/damianofalcioni/js-aruco2/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">a fork of the latter</a> to create a <a href="https://fodi.itch.io/arucontrol-construct3" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">basic Construct 3 template project</a>. Essentially this is a new input method: you can move different markers in front of a camera and based on their position and unique ID, things happen.</p>
<p>Fiducial markers could also enable <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Jd3-eiid-Uw" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">head tracking</a>, there are folks already <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ajoUzwe1bT0" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">using OpenTrack</a> to achieve this. I have a super basic (no real math included) prototype in Construct 3 that moves the camera perspective via a single ArUco marker on screen.</p>
<p>I also have a few ideas on how to utilize ArUco marker detection in video and/or tabletop games: either by using a camera fixed above the table looking down, or one placed in the middle of the table with the display and front camera facing up. Players place cards with ArUco codes which the phone detects and progresses the game.</p>
<h2>Hand tracking</h2>
<p>Ever since I came across <a href="https://github.com/handtracking-io/yoha" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Yoha</a>, I wanted to use it in a game. At first I'd like to make free Construct 3 project template with it. Then maybe something like Draw Something or possibly use it for one of the "level editor" based games.</p>
<h2>Multiplayer games without wireless networks</h2>
<p>I'm absolutely fascinated by <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Procedural_generation" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">procedural generation</a> in general, <a href="https://github.com/bryc/code/blob/master/jshash/PRNGs.md" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">PRNGs</a>, <a href="https://github.com/mxgmn/WaveFunctionCollapse" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">wave function collapse</a> and stuff like that. I can totally imagine a local multiplayer game, where people in the same room need to communicate by saying stuff to each other (think <a href="https://spaceteam.ca/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Spaceteam</a>, but not necessarily that chaotic), controlling their own players on their phone and making joint progress... all without the need for a Bluetooth or wifi connection. They just enter the same (short) seed at the beginning of the game (which predetermines what events will take place in the game and when) and then all "network communication" is carried out by the players as they talk to each other and enter stuff on their own device. Some ideas for actual games:</p>
<h3>Co-operative dungeon crawler with item teleportation</h3>
<p>Players are all alone in different areas of a large procedurally generated dungeon but can magically send things that are requested by other players (verbally) by entering "codes" (think TOTP). For example: one player is in bad shape after a fight but has no health potions: they ask if anyone has any; a second player volunteers to send one. The second player goes to their inventory, select the potion and selects the target player (eg. by color): a unique, time limited code is generated consisting of symbols, eg. "fire-water-stone-stone" or "4-1-2-7" and the item disappears from the inventory. The second player enters the code, which is validated using the original seed, the recipient player's color (ID) and a timeframe and if it check out, the health potion appears in their inventory.</p>
<h3>Video rental chain</h3>
<p>This idea I've always wanted to debut on a Halloween-themed game jam, but haven't had time to do it. The setting: all players work in different branches of a huge VHS rental network (like Blockbuster back in the day) and it's the busiest day of the year, there are a huge line of people wanting to rent horror films. Some titles are not in and players need to ask other players if they have it in their store (yes, this is the same Spaceteam recipe for a shouting match). If they do, they can put the tape in a pneumatic tube and quickly send it to another store. This part works exactly the method described in the previous idea. There's also a huge opportunity to come up with a bunch of funny non-existent movie titles and puns for existing movies.</p>
<h3>Escape room</h3>
<p>Nothing super innovative here: just take the premise of We Were Here and send items/codes to the other player(s) verbally.</p>
<h2>Real maps to game maps</h2>
<p>Although it's probably not an easy task to accomplish, but I'd like to find a way to import maps of actual cities to games (probably via <a href="https://www.openstreetmap.org/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">OpenStreetMap</a> if licensing is possible). Players could take advantage of their local knowledge by planning their routes to marked places (think airdrops in Dying Light); open world exploration / survival games could benefit from using real working cities as base maps instead of procedurally generated ones.</p>
<h2>Geolocation based games</h2>
<p>In the same neighborhood of the previous concept, I also have a few ideas (and even a prototype) for mobile games that require players to actually go to certain places. Back in 2016 I hacked together such a game that featured a bunch of images I shot around my hometown, coupled with short and cryptic text clues and players had to figure out where they were taken. The game showed the approximate distance of all targets and allowed players to request a further text clue (but this mean that they'll only get half of the points rewarded). When they figured out the location of a target they had to go there and the game only allowed marking one as found if they were within 10 meters of the target's recorded geolocation. I've started resurrecting this idea in 2022, it's about halfway done.</p>
<p>I also hastily prototyped a proof of concept in the same domain that was based on an idea nicked from the excellent UK show <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=82c2y94BvEA&amp;t=994s" title="Taskmaster UK S01E03@16:34" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Taskmaster</a>, where competitors had to draw something by walking around a field carrying a GPS device with a screen that allowed them to monitor their progress real time.</p>
<p> </p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Day Two</title>
        <author>
            <name>Fodi</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://blog.fodi.be/day-2/"/>
        <id>https://blog.fodi.be/day-2/</id>
            <category term="Blog"/>

        <updated>2022-12-02T12:02:53+01:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                    I've spent yesterday organizing notes and converting them to posts (check them out if you want) and I'm doing the&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                <p>I've spent yesterday organizing notes and converting them to posts (check them out if you want) and I'm doing the same today. I'll be mostly AFK this weekend so the next update will be on Monday.</p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Copterfields</title>
        <author>
            <name>Fodi</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://blog.fodi.be/copterfields/"/>
        <id>https://blog.fodi.be/copterfields/</id>
        <media:content url="https://blog.fodi.be/media/posts/5/coperfields.png" medium="image" />
            <category term="Prototype phase"/>
            <category term="GameDev"/>
            <category term="Ended"/>

        <updated>2022-12-02T12:01:52+01:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://blog.fodi.be/media/posts/5/coperfields.png" alt="" />
                    Background As Lasermagnet Games (my friend Tibor and me) we've joined the Toy Box Jam 3 in early Feb 2022&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <p><img src="https://blog.fodi.be/media/posts/5/coperfields.png" class="type:primaryImage" alt="" /></p>
                <h2>Background</h2>
<p>As <strong>Lasermagnet Games</strong> (my friend Tibor and me) we've joined the <a href="https://itch.io/jam/toy-box-jam-3"></a><a href="https://itch.io/jam/toy-box-jam-3" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Toy Box Jam 3</a> in early Feb 2022 and this time we didn't fail time management miserably and were able to maintain focus quite well, especially compared to most of our game jam attempts.</p>
<p>Although I'd still call Copterfields just a prototype due to the lack of content and suboptimal balance, I was (and frankly still am) quite satisfied with the end result. The game received a couple post-jam updates (including local multiplayer support), but development was halted in March 2022.</p>
<p>The last build is playable on Itch and I've kept a devlog during development too.</p>
<h2>Future plans</h2>
<p>I have no plans to continue development.</p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Video game remakes</title>
        <author>
            <name>Fodi</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://blog.fodi.be/video-game-remakes/"/>
        <id>https://blog.fodi.be/video-game-remakes/</id>
            <category term="Idea phase"/>
            <category term="GameDev"/>

        <updated>2022-12-02T14:00:36+01:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                    I have a growing list of existing (mostly popular) games that have main mechanics that I admire and want to&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                <p>I have a growing list of existing (mostly popular) games that have main mechanics that I admire and want to implement for various reasons.</p>
<ul>
<li>The challenge: I want to see if I can do it, in what timeframe and what aspects do I underestimate during the process.</li>
<li>Educational value: I can learn new things while implementing already existing, proven and well thought out mechanics. If I document the process others can learn too.</li>
<li>In some cases – if I'm satisfied with the result – I might release the source project (essentially a template) either for free or maybe for a fee.</li>
</ul>
<p>Here's the list of games I might attempt to partially remake.</p>
<h3>Wizard of Wor</h3>
<p>This was probably the first video game I got addicted to in Commodore 64 times. If I ever implement the base mechanics I'd love to add a few new ones, like destructible walls, 4 player support (with larger maps, maybe TDM/CTF modes).</p>
<h3>Plants vs Zombies</h3>
<p>I spent countless hours playing PvZ on PC and Android as well, I absolutely love the concept and I already started hacking together a template which uses roughly the same controls / mechanics but with a 2.5D side view where lanes are stacked on top of each other. I also have an idea for a fork: controlling the game completely by the keyboard, but not with the arrows, but by typing keywords (think Typing of the Dead or Epistory - Typing Chronicles).</p>
<h3>Heroes of Might and Magic 2±1</h3>
<p>I'd love to play a game with the same base mechanics but in a completely different world. Maybe a WWII or futuristic robot war theme?</p>
<h3>Airmech</h3>
<p>During the development of the Copterfields prototype / game jam entry I already implemented similar player movement (and beaming / building capabilities), but not combat. An Airmech clone would also be a great opportunity to venture into networked multiplayer territory, something that I haven't done yet.</p>
<h3>Kingdom series</h3>
<p>I had a lot of fun playing Kingdom: New Lands, until I didn't. The gorgeous art style and amazing audio probably played a huge part on why I spent over 50 hours playing a game that's so unforgiving at times. I didn't like the huge difference in stress levels between runs because of the RNG, but there are parts of the base mechanics that I'd love to implement. With a twist (that might or might not work): I'd like to try to make the whole level fit on the screen by placing multiple "rows" of it vertically and either adding vertical travel (think SimTower) or teleportation so it doesn't take minutes to get from one end of the level to the other. Making the whole level visible would unlock the possibility to add local multiplayer.</p>
<h3>Smash TV (or a similar twin stick action game)</h3>
<p>Even though I've never played Smash TV, I'd love to do a similar twin stick fighter/shooter with local multiplayer. I don't have an idea for the theme/lore yet though.</p>
<h3>QuizUp</h3>
<p>Back in 2014 (iirc) or 2015 I had a blast playing this (sometimes fake-)multiplayer trivia game. I had a quite competitive knowledge about certain TV shows (like The Office, Family Guy, South Park, The Sopranos, etc) and I was able to showcase that due to public scoreboards. When I started playing QuizUp also had player profiles and social features like chat which I thought probably could've been a great way to make new friends by allowing people of similar interested connect to each other, but it was removed later. A friend of mine also approached me years later with an idea very similar to QuizUp (including monetizable community-made question packs) - now that QuizUp is long gone (shut down in 2021) it might be worth a try to go after its market.</p>
<h3>Dr Mario</h3>
<p>This is a project I already started hacking together but abandoned. The base mechanics are brilliant and so simple that there are room for forks. One idea I have is to have low resolution pictures of objects in the background of a level (made up from the same colors of the "pills") and target would be to place pills so the right colors overlap to complete a picture (essentially a very hard drawing game).</p>
<h3>Ballance</h3>
<p>...just in 2D. I think the same mechanics (switching ball material / weight) would work great either in a top-down (similar to <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Rollin_(video_game)" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Rollin</a>) or side view.</p>
<h3>The Incredible Machine</h3>
<p>It was perfect the way it was, but I admit that I loved the second one even more because of the wacky cartoon characters. I'd just love to implement a bunch of objects, a level editor and let it loose on the unsuspecting public - that's you.</p>
<h3>Mahjong solitaire</h3>
<p>I already have a basic implementation, but I want to mix the gameplay with something totally different. Either by turning it into an action game (eg. you have to gather various resources - stone, wood, gold, whatever - against a time limit and build stuff to defend against waves of enemy attacks) or maybe something educational (use it as a language learning tool - pair up the same phrases/words in two different languages - an alternative flash card technique).</p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Level Editor Mayhem</title>
        <author>
            <name>Fodi</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://blog.fodi.be/level-editor-mayhem/"/>
        <id>https://blog.fodi.be/level-editor-mayhem/</id>
        <media:content url="https://blog.fodi.be/media/posts/3/lem.png" medium="image" />
            <category term="Prototype phase"/>
            <category term="GameDev"/>
            <category term="Continuing"/>

        <updated>2022-12-02T12:02:28+01:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://blog.fodi.be/media/posts/3/lem.png" alt="Level Editor Mayhem (working title)" />
                    Background Back in July 2021 I've started working on a competitive local multiplayer platformer under the working title Level Editor&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <p><img src="https://blog.fodi.be/media/posts/3/lem.png" class="type:primaryImage" alt="Level Editor Mayhem (working title)" /></p>
                <h2>Background</h2>
<p>Back in July 2021 I've started working on a competitive local multiplayer platformer under the working title Level Editor Mayhem. After having so much fun playing Ultimate Chicken Horse with friends on a big screen I wanted to make something similar, but with the twist of not having rounds or build phases, just doing everything real time. My friend <a href="https://teebor9.itch.io/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Tibor</a> joined the development early on providing graphics, new ideas and helping with the testing.</p>
<p>Development slowed down a bit after a month and a half and I died down gradually around the 3 month mark (last update was on September 24).</p>
<p>I meticulously ran a <a href="https://fodi.itch.io/level-editor-mayhem-prototype/devlog"></a><a href="https://fodi.itch.io/level-editor-mayhem-prototype/devlog" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">devlog</a> back in the day and all builds were made public from the start. The la(te)st version is available on <a href="https://fodi.itch.io/level-editor-mayhem-prototype"></a><a href="https://fodi.itch.io/level-editor-mayhem-prototype" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Itch</a>.</p>
<h2>Future plans</h2>
<p>This is a project that I really want to pursue (and possibly rewrite, not sure how the code aged). It probably has enough mechanics as is, it just needs boring stuff (menu, lobby, settings, etc), some more polish, playtesting and maybe a few more levels. Oh and a proper title.</p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Main themes for video games</title>
        <author>
            <name>Fodi</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://blog.fodi.be/main-themes-for-video-games/"/>
        <id>https://blog.fodi.be/main-themes-for-video-games/</id>
            <category term="Idea phase"/>
            <category term="GameDev"/>

        <updated>2022-12-02T12:02:15+01:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                    This list contains "main themes" for video games. Some were dreamt, some were designated to be on theme for a&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                <p>This list contains "main themes" for video games. Some were dreamt, some were designated to be on theme for a specific game jam, but most of them were manifested while drinking beers with my good friend <a href="https://itch.io/profile/teebor9" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Tibor</a> (by either him or me).</p>
<h3>Windy (physics puzzle)</h3>
<ul>
<li>2D side or top-down view</li>
<li>Player places permanent or switchable wind generators (like fans in The Incredible Machine) on a level that already includes walls and hazards, entry and exit point(s).</li>
<li>Objects (balls of various size/weight) will start appearing at the entry point(s) and their movement will be affected by gravity, wind generators and other objects (collision). The objective is to guide (the right type of) objects (to the right type of) exit point(s).</li>
</ul>
<h3>Junk tower defense</h3>
<ul>
<li>Player collects various household scrap parts during the day, builds towers, enemies will invade during the night (the player can fight them also, but is quite vulnerable)</li>
<li>Basic materials: iron scrap, electronic scrap, plastic, wood, glass, household supplies, chemicals, water</li>
<li>Special materials: vacuum cleaner, buzz saw, glue, tennis/pool balls, lighter fluid, flint, microwave ovens (magnetron)</li>
<li>Player finds blueprints or invents new stuff, can dismantle towers</li>
</ul>
<h3>Tower defense at sea</h3>
<ul>
<li>Build static or movable platforms on sea</li>
<li>Extract oil / mine minerals</li>
</ul>
<h3>Reverse city builder</h3>
<ul>
<li>Strategically destroy/dismantle dense (previously overpopulated, now abandoned), badly planned parts of cities</li>
</ul>
<h3>Dungeon Bouncer (dungeon crawler / physics puzzle)</h3>
<ul>
<li>Top down dungeon crawler view</li>
<li>You move the player by touch/drag aiming (adjusting angle and maybe "power" too): when released, the player will start moving in the specified direction bouncing off walls, colliding with enemies (attacking them), collecting items, destroying barrels/boxes, etc.</li>
<li>The number of bounces or the length of a "run" is limited but can be extended by items or spending XP.</li>
</ul>
<p> </p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Day One</title>
        <author>
            <name>Fodi</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://blog.fodi.be/day-one/"/>
        <id>https://blog.fodi.be/day-one/</id>
            <category term="Blog"/>

        <updated>2022-12-01T13:25:44+01:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                    I'm starting an experiment today. My virtual idea drawer is a mess and I need to do something about it.
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                <p>I'm starting an experiment today. My virtual idea drawer is a mess and I need to do something about it. Google Keep notes, text files all over my Dropbox, freaking audio recordings on my phone...</p>
<p>About a month ago I decided that I have to put a pause on making money (working on other people's stuff) because I clearly failed at my attempt to mix jobs with pet projects / creative hobbies in a healthy ratio. So I'm designating this December as "get your (own) shit together" month.</p>
<p>Today I'm starting this blog and I'll update it every day in December, hoping that publicly logging my progress helps me stay on track.</p>
<p>As first order of business I'm taking inventory and organizing all ideas, abandoned projects and half-assed attempts and putting them on either a "might do" or "probably won't do" pile. After that's done, I'm going to choose the first one either by preference or at random and get hacking and blogging.</p>
<p>Although I'm slightly terrified of it, but I'm also planning to stream stuff (especially game development), but I'm not quite sure that's a good idea at this point. We'll see.</p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
</feed>
